Hello everyone, welcome to the computer networking courses.
In this today's world, computer network formed the foundation of almost everything we do,
from browsing the internet sending emails streaming videos to connect smart devices and
support a global business.
Networking enables computer devices to communicate, share resources, access information
seamlessly across the globe.
This force provided a comprehensive understanding, how network operates, how data travel
from one device to another, and the protocol technologies that made model communication
possible.
You will learn about network models, IPetas, routing, switching, network security, wireless
communication and lot more.
The more essential skills for everyone pursuing a career in IT or in cybersecurity or just
for a interview.
So there's a lot of things that you're going to learn in this course.
In this course, there will be a structured job-ready skills on being supported.
You can ask me question anytime, I will get back to you and whether or not for the
hours.
So what will this course will cover?
Like, what is a computer, okay, how could a computer communicates with each other, and
like what did the computer components?
Then we networked, talk about the network itself.
What is networking?
What is like, if someone is a networking, you should say that to, this is a complete
definition of saying that this is a networking, okay.
Understand the practical user network, where we use network in our company, which type
of network we should go with, okay.
So when you are a network administrator, you have to choose, either you go with first
technology, you go to be a startup technology, you go to be a ranked topology, what are you
going to be a matched topology?
It depends on the situation.
Most of the time, it will be a ranked topology because of minimum downtime, however, so
these are the things.
And then we talk about the ethernet, actual image, the type of ethernet we have, like
some ethernet support, fire distance, some sort of distance, and the type of ethernet we
are going to use, it's Rj45 or whatever.
So this is all we are going to understand in this course.
Next.
So we are working in device, like tap of networking device, we have, we have switches,
we have access point, we have a lot of things, we have 14 firewall, okay.
We have a S domain, there's a lot of things.
And what each networking device operations, like what, why we use this particular switch,
why particular router, why particular access point, these are all we are going to discuss
in the scenarios according to it.
Next.
Connect to the cloud.
And now we will talk about the cables to stick pair fiber optical cables, a wireless network
of wired network, a wireless in which we come with a Wi-Fi access point.
Then wired versus wireless, choosing the right connection, which we need, we have to go
a wired wireless for cloud computing.
Next.
This is a very important model, which we talk about the most, most, we can say that most
controls are topic, and the most are expression in an interview in a practical way, everything,
a HR model and TCP model, and there's a key difference between the, these models.
Now I put us, this is a very important thing, you have to know IP address, tap of IP
addresses, IPv4 IPv6, their subnet, public private, what is their static IPs, what are
the dynamic IPs, default gateways, blah, blah, blah.
Now we also going to see a command night interface, CLI tools for networking diagnosis,
like where we use Bing, where we use FTP, where we use telenet, where we use, and as
we look up there, we use path, Bing, where you use trace rate, where you use net set.
There's a lot of things that you can reduce, we are going to discuss in this course.
Next.
I should show networking services here, so here, we're going to talk about DHCP remote
administrator, to old DNS, what is ARP, what is PGP, why it is OSP week.
So when you come in a network, you have to understand this thing.
And if, even if you're not going to come in a network, you are going to, in a subbar
go to field, even that you have to be know what is these networking services are, why
we use them, and how the effect of a network, how the effect the devices.
Next, move over to the infrastructure, so there is a internet extra, and these are the
simple one, and DMV, why we use DMZ, this is important, why use firewall, this is important.
And there's a virtual power network, which is a VPN set for everyone know this.
Next move over.
Now, some business copy comes at int rules, real network, we're going to, how we make
a real network, how why we need a real network, and how we do routing in a network, what
the ports, and why, why the ports are very much important, what is an ad, that is a network
address translation, and pad is a port address translation, so why we using an ad and pad.
So this is a network transfer, traffic analysis, like how we can do a network traffic
measure, and what tools are going to help us, then there's a door, so these are the
door set, which occurs, how we're security, some hardware, and this is all.
So these things we are going to cover in this, and if you are going to join a, like you
are going to join a job, in a practical world, in this course, you get all the information
all the related data that you are going to practice user, and you will, when you are working
on a office, you understand that this course helped me in there, okay, and if you're
going to interview, the same thing happens, because this course, I designed in a way
that no more questions asked by interview out of this, okay.
So for me, my name is Sorkumar, and I'm in a network industry for more than five years.
I have a deep analysis, and just to be tell you, you know, one year, I'm going from
L1 to L2, okay, so I know how to complete the basic, and how to move ahead, like move
ahead with others, like we, now I'm in a realistic role, but I know basic, I know advanced
things in a network, in a cyber security, and the one that, playing a very important role
in my company, in a, both in a cyber security, in a network, so touch it, and we are going
to discuss a lot of things here, just set and relax and listen carefully, make notes,
that's it.
Thank you very much.